Anderson Cardoso

Front-End Engineer | Mobile Engineer

<u>andersoncardoso.dev@gmail.com</u> • +55 (51) 99724-5468 • RS, Brazil <u>LinkedIn</u> • <u>Github</u> • <u>Portfolio</u>

ABOUT

Front End and Mobile Developer, specialized in React Native and React Js.

Have been working professionally with React and React Native since 2021, developing solutions and enhancing application performance in the health, logistic and insurance sectors.

Have a strong understanding of UX/UI principles and am deeply committed to app quality and usability. Focus on identifying true needs and delivering greater value than just a simple digital product.

Take great pride in crafting clean and efficient code, always focused on processes, as they are what truly make a difference in the success of a great project.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Worked professionally with React and React Native for 3 years, developing solutions and improving application performance in the health, logistics, and insurance sectors.
- Main technologies include React Native, Expo, React, Next, Vite, TypeScript and JavaScript.
- Currently working as a Software Engineer at WeFit, specialized in white-label mobile applications.
- Regarding soft skills, mentioned as a helpful professional always ready to collaborate with colleagues. Keen eye for detail, excels at problem-solving, prioritizes code quality, fast learner, and creative thinker
- Notable achievements include increasing 3.4 score in a health application at Play Store and 2.4 at Apple Store, with more than 15 millions downloads registered.

WORK EXPERIENCE

WeFit - Digital Service Design, March 2023 – Present *São Paulo, Brazil · Remote*

WeFit - Mobile Engineer with React Native Expo using TypeScript | React Native Paper | Babel | Expo Router, October 2024 – Present

São Paulo, Brazil · Remote

A white-label logistic application designed to register asynchronous deliveries in a B2B context, including location tracking, made by React Native Expo using TypeScript.

- Developed and integrated new features in a hybrid mobile app project using React Native Expo with TypeScript.
- Reduced navigation delays by 25% through the refactoring of Expo Router structure.
- Lowered application bundle size by 40MB by switching to the .aab format.
- Built and released versions on Play Store, brought to a white-label architecture.
- Performed an in-depth review and classification of application workflows, pinpointing and addressing bugs, logical flaws, and security vulnerabilities, resulting in a 40% improvement in overall application reliability.

WeFit - Front-End Software Developer using React | Redux | Styled Components | TypeScript, October 2024 - Present

São Paulo, Brazil · Remote

A web application for managing the logistics process of many B2B contracts, providing a tracking system, delivery time and delay charts, driver registration, and staff management.

- Developed automation through Bash scripts to standardize and enhance the reliability of the build process.
- Responsible for supporting any changes or issues in the web application.
- Responsible for building and releasing the web application in the production environment

WeFit - Mobile Engineer with React Native CLI using TypeScript | React Native Paper | Realm | Context API, March 2023 - September 2024

São Paulo. Brazil · Remote

A white-label health super application focused on the customer side, enabling medical appointments, account financial management, and a refund ordering system, with 4 apps released, and over 10 million downloads, made by React Native CLI using TypeScript.

- Overseeing a team of 6 software engineers in a hybrid mobile application project using React Native CLI with TypeScript in a white-label structure for more than 4 companies.
- Served as the main code reviewer for the team, preventing 14% of bugs and pattern mistakes.
- Refactored 28% of the codebase, including the service layer, reducing rework and estimated development time.
- Increased reusability of global components by 43% through refactoring to the Composition Pattern.

• Conducted comprehensive analysis and optimization of application processes and flows, which enhanced application performance and user experience, improving the app from 1.4 points to 4.6 points in Play Store.

Front End Web Developer with Angular 7 using TypeScript, March 2022 – June 2022 *Infocap TI*, Novo Hamburgo, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil

An insurance web application designed for insurance brokers, providing forms to research the top insurance agencies and generating reports with the best proposals for each case, made by Angular using TypeScript.

- Developed new components for the main company library using Angular 7.
- Refactored the forms factory which used JSON to render new forms, minimizing complexity.
- Analyzed and categorized application processes, identifying bugs, logic errors, and vulnerabilities, and resolving 42% of the project's issues.

FullStack Developer with React Vite using JavaScript | MaterialUI | Node Js | Express Js | AWS | EC2, November 2021 – February 2022

Freelance, Novo Hamburgo, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil

A web application that allows users to add text content, images, and links to populate a hotel's website. It was developed using React CRA and Node.js with Express.js, deployed on AWS EC2, and used MongoDB Atlas Cloud for data storage.

- Developed a website and dashboard, divided into micro-frontends for content management and display, using React and Vite.
- Developed a RESTful API with Node and Express.js using TypeScript for inserting hotel data and images to populate the website.
- Set up AWS instances and managed production environments for deploying both APIs and websites, including configuring servers, integrating MongoDB databases in the cloud, and ensuring secure and scalable deployments.

EDUCATION

Lutheran University of Brazil (Ulbra), Torres, RS - Brazil *Associate's degree, Software development*, GPA: 9.3, Jul 2024

Ada Tech, São Paulo, SP - Brazil

Technical Course Santander Coders, Software development, GPA: 8.9, March 2022

CERTIFICATIONS & SKILLS

- Dynamic Course of English as a Second Language Times Idiomas Nov 2023
- Advanced Projects in React.JS DIO Aug 2021
- Scrum Agile Methodologies DIO Jul 2021

LANGUAGES

- English Fluent
- **Portuguese** *Native*